7,549.
噢，质数
Oh, please. Prime.
4,021.
哈, 不错的尝试
Ah, nice try.
不是质数
Not prime.
好吧, Ford中尉, 599.
Okay, Lieutenant Ford, 599.
我可不管这个数字是不是质数
I don't care if it's a prime number or not.
- 噢，来吧. 是还是不是?
- 不是
- Oh, come on. Yes or no?
- No.
难以相信. 10个了
It's incredible. 10 for 10.
- 他太厉害了
- 这些问题把我搞得烦死了
- He's terrible.
- So I suck nat prime/not prime.
不知怎么今晚我总是想睡觉
Somehow I'm going to sleep tonight.
从这点来看, 这已经不是判断是不是质数的问题了
At this point, it's gone way beyond
you not knowing your prime numbers.
这是一个判断真假的游戏
It's a true/false game.
从统计学上来说, 单单是猜测的话,
你也至少会答对一半
Statistically, just by guessing,
you should be getting at least half of these right.
听好, 993.
Look, 993.
- 质数
- 嗨, 这个不难啊
- Prime.
- Come on. That's an easy one.
Hays, 你都听到了?
Are you hearing this, Hays?
没有
Not really.
我想我是太投入我的工作了
I guess I've been too busy doing my job.
我们已经穿过Atlantis城的这个区域了, Killjoy博士
We've already been through
this section of Atlantis, Dr. Killjoy.
你不可能没有听到
It's structurally sound.
Ford中尉...
Lieutenant Ford...
你介不介意作一下
统计学不可能性研究这篇论文的研究对象?
Would you mind being a subject of
research paper on statistical improbabilities?
这就是我在高中痛揍像你这样的小子所得的回报, 是么?
This some sort of payback for guys like me
beating up guys like you in high school, right?
Rodney, 今天在郊区发现了什么没有?
So, Rodney,
what's it like out there in the suburbs today?
基本上, 除了一个位于高层的储藏室
Essentially, with the exception
of the upper-level storage room,
我们可爱及天才的Dumais
告诉我它目前没有危险
which the lovely and talented Dumais
informs me is in no immediate danger,
这一片支墩没有什么问题
this pier is in relatively good shape.
即使是被随风暴而来的洪水洗劫之后?
Even after the flooding from the storm?
好吧, 这里阴暗潮湿, 气味也很难闻,
Well, it's dark, it's damp, and it smells terrible,
但从一个工程师的立场来看, 我们都很好.
but from an engineering standpoint, we're good.
回来吧
Head back.
准备回去
Heading back.
好了, 你们这些小丑, 听好了
All right, you clowns, listen up.
我并不是经常有这个机会, 所以好好听好了...
I don't often get a chance to say this, so savor it...
你们都干得很好
good work, boys and girls.
现在我们回家吧
Let's go home.
等等, 等等, 等等.
Wait, wait, wait.
Johnson和Wagner找不到了
We're missing Johnson and Wagner.
Wagner, Johnson, 你们在哪儿?
Wagner, Johnson, what's your position?
我们需要支援!
We need backup!
- 它们正朝我们过来!
- 什么?
- They're coming at us!
- What?
它们在哪?
Where are they?
这条走廊
Down this corridor.
我们出发
We're on our way.
Johnson.
Johnson, 你还好吧?
Johnson, are you okay?
McKay...他死了
McKay... he's dead.
Johnson, 这里到底发生了什么?
Johnson, what happened here?
- 它们抓住了他
- 谁抓住了他?
- They got him.
- Who got him?
镇静. 这什么都没有.
Calm down. There's nothing here.
你看不见它们?
Can't you see them?
它们到处都是!
They're everywhere!
Beckett, 我需要一支医疗队过来
Beckett, I need a medical team down here, stat.
没用了
It's no use.
她死了
She's gone.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第13集 热区
Season 1 : Episode 13 Hot Zone
McKay, 我是Beckett博士
McKay, this is Dr. Beckett.
急救具体是什么性质的?
What exactly is the nature of the emergency?
太迟了
他们已经死了
It's too late.
They're gone.
- 谁死了? 怎么死的?
- Wagner 和 Johnson.
- Who's gone? How?
- Wagner and Johnson.
我需要一个隔离小组过来.
I need a containment team here.
什么意思?
I'm sorry?
隔离小组? 为什么?
A containment team? Why?
人们不会只是看到了什么然后就倒下死了, 中尉
People don't just see things
and drop dead, Lieutenant.
最近一个小时
我们都在调查这个城市中未勘测的区域
We've spent the last hour
surveying unexplored areas of the city.
我想Wagner和Johnson接触到了什么东西
I think Wagner and Johnson
were exposed to something.
如果他们被感染了
那我们也很可能被感染了
And if they were infected,
there's a very good chance that we were too.
在我们搞清楚我们面对的是什么之前
我建议进行四级隔离
I recommend a level-four quarantine
until we know what we're dealing with.
同意. Carson, 你都听到了?
Agreed. Carson, you hear all that?
是的. 我们将会进入紧急状态并尽快处理
Aye. We'll get into our hazmat gear and head down.
先不要动. 等我先向Weir博士报告
Sit tight. I'll make sure Dr. Weir is briefed.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
好了, 你们都听到了
女士们, 先生们, 跟我来
Okay, you heard the man.
Follow me, ladies and gentlemen.
这么说等着, 为什么?
我们要一直呆在这里?
So wait, what? We're just going to stay here?
对, 是这样安排的
That's the plan. Yes.
我可以说这实在是一个糟糕的安排么?
May I say it's a terrible one?
不, 你不能这么说
No, you may not.
我想我们应该尽快离开这里
I think we should get the hell out of here.
如果它是靠空气传播的
那我们已经被感染上了
If it is an airborne agent,
we may already be infected.
返回到城市中只会让其他人面临危险
Heading back to the city would only
endanger the rest of the population.
但如果我们还没有被感染呢?
But what if we're not infected yet?
我们无从知道
There's no way of knowing.
但我感觉没事. 我感觉非常好!
But I feel fine. I feel perfectly fine!
讨论结束
End of discussion.
Peterson, 我们必须呆在这里
Peterson, we're staying here.
事实上, 等一下
Actually, wait a second.
各位, 跟我来
Everyone, follow me.
他们已经开始建立四级隔离了
They've begun to institute a level-four quarantine.
这不会真是一场生物传染, 对么?
It can't really be a biological infection, can it?
我不知道这到底是什么...
I have no idea what it is...
但我同意我们应该安全地对待它
并且在城市所有有人的地方进行就地隔离
But I agree we should play it safe
and initiate self-regulated quarantine
in all populated sections of the city.
太过激烈了吧
That's pretty severe.
我们已经知道曾经某时
亚特兰蒂斯人确实经历过一场瘟疫
We've known for some time that
the Ancients suffered from a plague.
如果McKay他们以某种方式
不经意间发现了它并且已经被感染了
If McKay and his team have somehow
stumbled upon it and become infected,
我们必须采取一切可能的措施防止它扩散
we'll need to take every precaution
to prevent an outbreak.
好吧
All right.
我们将会关闭所有的大门
让大家都呆在各自所在的地方
We will suspend any and all gate activity
and keep everyone where they are,
重复一遍, 直到我们确切的弄明白
到底是什么杀死了Wagner和Johnson.
again, just until we have a clearer picture
of exactly what it is that killed Wagner and Johnson.
- 你根本就没有投入
- 不, 我投入了
- You have not been practicing.
- Yes, I have.
如果这是真正的格斗的话...
If this was really a fight...
如果这是真正的格斗
我现在已经开枪把你打倒了
if this was really a fight,
I would have shot you by now.
要知道, 不管我在这上面花费多少时间
仍然不会是你的对手
You know, no matter how many hours I put into this,
you're still going to kick my ass.
这不是指在我们的练习中取胜
It is not for the winning that we practice.
嗯, 那是什么意思?
Well, what's the point?
各位, 请注意
May I have everyone's attention, please.
我们现在碰到一个可疑的医学情况,
根据Beckett的建议
We've run into a questionable medical situation,
and at Dr. Beckett's suggestion,
我们不得不决定将这个城市就地隔离
we have decided to put the city into
a self-regulated quarantine.
在这之后至少两个小时内
我们需要所有人呆在原处
For at least the next couple of hours,
I need everyone to stay where they are
并且报告所有在走廊走动的人
and report anyone moving freely through the halls.
希望你们能够理解. 谢谢
I hope you understand. Thank you.
这到底是什么?
What the hell is this?
你带了无线电么?
Did you bring your radio?
这就是Wagner和Johnson所勘查的区域么?
Isn't this the same section
Wagner and Johnson were exploring?
是的
Yes.
这就是说我们在沿原路返回?
So we're retracing their steps?
是的. 不用担心
我的动机完全是出于自我防护
That's right. Don't worry.
My motivations are based entirely on self-preservation.
等等, 等等, 等等.
Wait, wait, wait.
Ford是对的
这会不会增加我们受到感染的可能性?
Ford's right.
Doesn't this increase our chances of getting infected?
好吧
All right.
让我好好给你解释清楚, 好么?
Let me spell this out for you, okay?
如果细菌不是通过空气传播的
If there is a bacterial agent and it is not airborne,
那我们四处看看相对来说就是安全的
then it should be relatively safe
for us to look around
只要我们采取了适当的预防措施
as long as we take the proper precautions.
但是...
However...
如果是通过空气传播的
那我们就很可能已经把感染了
if it is an airborne agent, then there's a
very good chance we've already been infected.
好吧, 难道我们不应该等Beckett来作确切的诊断么?
Well, shouldn't we wait for Dr. Beckett to decide that?
那些人到这里来只有12小时
Those men were only down there for 12 hours.
即使他们立刻就被感染
那潜伏期也是非常短的
Even if they were infected right away,
that's an alarmingly short incubation period.
现在, 如果有人已经被感染了...
噢, 我不知道, 可能我们...
Now, if anyone else is infected...
as in, oh, I don't know, maybe us,
所剩时间已经不多了, 中尉
seconds are going to count, Lieutenant.
好了, 手电
All right, light.
我们走
Let's go.
所有人, 呆在原地
Everybody, stay here.
Ford
Ford.
- 你刚刚告诉我...
- 所有人, 除了Ford, 呆在原地
- You just told me...
- Everybody except Ford stay here.
你认为我应该自己一个人进去?
You think I'm going in there by myself?
不要碰任何东西
Don't touch anything.
这可不好
This is not good.
我是这里的最高军事指挥官
I'm ranking military officer here.
是的, 我很清楚这点, 少校
Yes, I'm aware of that, Major.
无线电联系不到你, 而我们必须快速行动
You were off radio, and we had to act quickly.
所有这些已经付诸实施的方案
Now, this is all protocol that was put into place
在此次考察之前很久就已经制定好了
long before this expedition even began.
Bates正在我身边
并且我们同意这是最好的实施方案
Bates is here with me,
and we agreed this was the best plan of action.
好吧, 好吧
All right. All right.
我和Teyla正过来跟你们会合
Teyla and I are coming up to join you.
我们正在就地隔离, 少校
We're in a self-regulated quarantine, Major.
每个人都要呆在原地
Everyone stays where they are.
从东边的支墩到这里差不多有一英里
They're nearly a mile away on the east pier.
你认为我从这里走到控制室真的会有什么危险么?
Do you really think I'm in any sort of danger
walking from here to the control room?
从这点上说, 我们不知道他们在哪接触到的病毒
At this point, we don't know
where they contracted the virus.
这是一个医学状况, John.
This is a medical situation, John.
只有经过授权的、穿有防护服的人才被允许自由走动
Only authorized personnel in
hazmat suits are allowed to roam freely.
这些规则作用于任何人身上, 包括你
Those rules apply to everyone, including you.
好吧, 那叫个人给我送一套防护服来
Well, then get someone to bring me a hazmat suit.
每个穿戴防护服的人都在忙着布置实验室
来应对可能爆发的疾病
Everyone in hazmat is busy configuring
the lab to deal with a possible outbreak.
目前, 只要机会允许
我一定会派个人来接你
Now, if an opportunity arises,
I will send someone to come get you,
不过在此之前, 我们只能通过无线电联系
but in the meantime, radio contact will have to do.
好吧
All right.
那就...让我们保持联系
Just...keep us in the loop.
会的
Will do.
这些破碎敞开容器中的任何一个都有可能
释放出病毒, 杀死了Johnson和Wagner
Any number of these smashed and open containers could
have released the virus that killed Johnson and Wagner.
那这种东西怎么可能活了这么些年?
And how would something like that
survive for all these years?
病毒可以长时间保持休眠状态.
Viruses can remain dormant for long periods.
希望可以在数据库中找到答案.
I'm hoping the answer will be found in the database.
- 好吧, 我想我们应该...
- 是的, 是的, 是的.
- Okay, I think that we have to...
- Yes, yes, yes.
看不出跟古人的其他系统有什么网络连接
Doesn't appear to be networked in
with the rest of the Ancient systems.
事实上, 正如你看到的, 这只保存了
In fact, if you look, it only contains information
在这个房间里所进行的实验的信息
about the experiments that took place in this room.
Weir, 我是McKay.
Weir, it's McKay.
说吧, Rodney.
Go ahead, Rodney.
- Beckett在哪?
- 在路上
- Where's Beckett?
- On his way.
让整个医疗队都穿上防护服需要一些时间
It takes some time to load
a whole medical team into suits.
好吧, 看起来我们偶然发现了什么
我发现了...一个小麻烦
Well, we seem to have stumbled across
something that I find... a little troubling.
这不是我想听到的
That's not what I wanted to hear.
我想我们找到了一个古人的病毒实验室
I think we may have found an ancient viral lab.
Wagner和Johnson一定是在这里被感染的
Wagner and Johnson must have been exposed here.
目前, 查看所有这些数据需要数周的时间
Now, it'd take weeks to sift through all this data,
而且, 我们也不知道古人到底是
and there's no way of knowing whether the Ancients
仅仅只是研究这些病毒
或者是在积极地制造它们...
were just studying the viruses
or actively creating them...
不管是那种情况, 风暴已经把这里破坏得一塌糊涂
Either way, the storm has done
quite a number on this place,
并且我们已经...
and I've got...
它在你上面!
It's all over you!
他们在你上面!
They're all over you!
让她躺下
Get her off.
告诉Beckett快点赶来
Tell Beckett to pick up the pace.
我们刚刚失去另外一个队员
I've just lost another member of our team.
Peterson在哪?
Where's Peterson?
什么?
What?
Peterson.
是的, 好了, 我想我们找到他了
Yes, okay, I think we have him.
他正在找路回来
He's trying to make his way back.
应该没事的
It should be okay.
Grodin正在锁住走廊中所有的门
然后切断整个区域的电源
Grodin is locking all the doors in the hallway
and killing power to the entire section.
你需要派人去阻止他
You need to send someone to stop him.
都在控制之中, Rodney...
It's under control, Rodney...
不, Elizabeth, 不在控制之中
No, Elizabeth, it's not under control.
他所知道的古人的科技不比我少
He knows almost as much about
Ancient technology as I do.
你所做的一切至多也只能让他慢一点
At the very most,
what you're doing will just slow him down.
那条走廊通向哪里?
Where does that hallway lead?
一直到这里
Straight here.
Peterson, 我是Elizabeth Weir.
Peterson, this is Elizabeth Weir.
能听到我说话么?
Can you hear me?
我无法想象这整个经历是多么的令人恐惧
I can't imagine how frightening
this whole ordeal must be,
不过Beckett博士已经找到了你们其他队员
并且开始医治他们
but Dr. Beckett has reached the rest
of your team and begun to treat them.
现在, 你现在最应该做的就是返回去
Now, I think the best thing
for you to do is to head back.
如果Beckett证明你完全健康
我们保证你可以尽快回到城市中来
If Beckett gives you a clean bill of health, we'll make
sure you get back to the city as soon as possible.
你确信他能够听到么?
Are you sure he can hear me?
肯定
Positive.
你能让通过这些门更困难一些么?
Can you do anything to make it harder
to get through those doors?
我可以试试
I can try.
好了, 你看起来非常好
Well, you seem perfectly fine.
Dumais在她突然不好之前, 看起来也非常好
Well, Dumais seemed fine right up
to the point where she wasn't.
我已经让他们在走廊上搭了一小块地方
I've had them set up
a small field station down the corridor.
我们已经开始尸体解剖了
We've already started the autopsies.
有什么看法?
Any ideas?
从现在来看,
你一切都好, 所以我不会...
From what we can tell,
you're all in good shape, so I wouldn't...
不要再告诉我我一切都好了, Carson.
stop trying to convince me I'm fine, Carson.
我想我们更加了解
I think we all know better.
- 我只是想...
- 我们搞完了么?
- I was just trying to...
- Are we done here?
是的
Yes.
我要看看我可以从数据库中找到什么
I'm going to see what I can get from the database.
尸体解剖有什么结果, 马上告诉我
Let me know what the autopsy shows up.
好的
All right.
噢, 告诉你那些病理学家
从他们的头部开始
Oh, and tell your pathologists
to start with their heads.
必须有人做些什么
Someone has to do something.
我们正在做
We are doing something.
Grodin正在想办法限制门的控制...
Grodin's working on a plan to limit door controls...
这还不够好
必须有人去阻止他
That's not good enough.
Someone has to go out there and stop him.
我和Teyla已经准备好了
Teyla and I are ready.
少校, 我们已经...
Major, we've been...
Peterson的想法很明显是错误的
他将会让城市中的所有人处于危险之中
Peterson obviously isn't thinking straight,
and he's endangering the entire population of the city.
我们现在仍然不知道我们所对付的病毒的习性
We don't yet know the nature
of the virus we're dealing with.
这仍然只是一个医学状况
This is still a medical situation.
我们没必要浪费时间了
我要出去了
We don't have time for this. I'm heading out.
Grodin, 封住体育馆.
Grodin, seal the gym.
这到底是怎么回事?
What the hell is this?
你自己说的
你是最高军事指挥官
You said so yourself.
You are the ranking military officer.
我不能让你有机会感染病毒
I can't chance you getting infected.
我不能让你有机会感染病毒. Bates?
I can't chance you getting infected. Bates?
是的, 长官
Yes, sir.
打开体育馆
Unlock the gym.
遵命, 长官
Yes, sir.
站住, Bates.
Stand down, Bates.
这里不归你做主, 少校.
You are not in command here, Major.
好吧, 我们少数服从多数
Well, we'll agree to disagree.
Bates, 把门打开
Bates, open the door.
不要
Don't.
Elizabeth, 他正朝你那边过来
Elizabeth, he's heading right for you.
所以我们一定要制止他
So we'll stop him.
我们会劝阻他, 我们会堵住他的路...
We'll talk him down, we'll block his way...
Bates中士, 我现在命令你立刻打开
体育馆到医学实验室之间所有的门
Sergeant Bates, I am ordering you to open up
the doors between the gym and the med lab right now.
我们准备出去
We're heading out.
对不起, 夫人
I'm sorry, Ma'am.
现在这都不要紧, 是么?
Doesn't really matter now, does it?
Beckett博士?
Dr. Beckett?
我已经有了最开始两位遇难者的初步解剖结果
I have the preliminary autopsy results
on the first two victims, Sir.
有什么值得关注的?
Anything of interest?
他们都死于大脑动脉瘤破裂
They both died of a ruptured saccular brain aneurysm,
这真是太不寻常了
which, in and of itself, isn't all that remarkable.
我的意思是, 两个站在一起的人
I mean, sure, the chances of two people
standing next to each other
同时死于这种原因在统计学上是不可能的
and dying of it is statistically improbable, yes,
不过这不是我们所希望的最终原因,
因为我知道你说过...
but it's not the smoking gun we were hoping for,
because I know you said...
直接说真正原因, Biro博士
Get to the good part, Dr. Biro.
对不起, 先生
Sorry, Sir.
真正引起我们关注的是
这两起动脉瘤的破裂
What's truly interesting
is that both ruptures happened
正巧都发生在相同的区域
刚好在视觉皮层
in exactly the same place,
right above the visual cortex.
那么第三个呢? Dumais?
And the third one? Dumais?
刚好轮到她了, 先生
Just getting to her now, sir.
我会告诉你的
I'll let you know.
她是说, "大脑动脉瘤," 对么?
She did say, "brain aneurysm," right?
是的
That's right.
这是我今天听到的最好的消息了
让我给你看些东西
That's the best news I've heard all day.
Let me show you something.
你本不应该在Bates中士面前破坏Weir博士的威信的
You should not have undermined Dr. Weir's
authority in front of sergeant Bates.
有时候, Elizabeth先作出了一个决定,
然后就困在那里面了    这就是问题
Sometimes, Elizabeth makes a decision
early on and gets locked into it. That's a problem.
她并不是唯一遭受这种苦恼的人
She is not the only one who suffers
from that affliction.
Weir博士, 我是Sheppard.
Dr. Weir, this is Sheppard.
我和Teyla已经准备好出去了
Teyla and I are ready to head out.
Peterson的位置在哪儿?
What's Peterson's location?
Elizabeth
Elizabeth.
他在E-19区, 第三层
He's in section E-19, level three.
我们走
Let's head out.
我没有读完整个条目
因为它实在是太长了
I haven't read the entire entry
because it's incredibly long,
不过这看起来像我们这些家伙
but this looks like our guy.
六小时休眠
重复出现的幻觉, 然后, 在这之后,
Six-hour hibernation,
recurring visions, and, best of all,
我们最后...
大脑出血或者动脉瘤
so I've left it to last...
brain hemorrhage or aneurysms.
这听起来非常熟悉
That definitely sounds familiar.
也许这里有讲如何...
Maybe there's something in here about how to...
不!
No!
抱歉
Sorry.
Rodney.
我刚才看见什么东西了
I've been seeing things.
从什么时候开始的?
Since when?
大约一个小时了
About an hour.
开始你会认为这只是你的眼睛在欺骗你, 不过最终...
First you think it's just your eyes
playing tricks on you, but eventually...
它们变得更糟
they get worse.
你也是?
You too?
他们直冲你过来
They come right at you.
看起来像鬼魂
It's like a ghost.
我已经去检查过了调查计划
I've been going over the survey schedule.
Johnson和Wagner从他们的位置出发
Johnson and Wagner started off on their own,
不过接着一小时后将穿过Dumais所经过的路线
but then crossed paths with Dumais an hour later.
Dumais差不多刚好在Johnson和Wagner之后一小时死去
Dumais died almost exactly
an hour after Johnson and Wagner.
他们接下来碰到的是谁?
Who did they meet up with next?
我现在最关心的是Dumais接下来碰到的是谁
My greater concern is who Dumais met up with next.
Dumais?
她碰到的是谁?
Who did she run into?
我
Me.
她碰到了Hays...
She ran into Hays...
和我
and me.
我们是下一波
We're next.
Peterson博士, 是你么?
Dr. Peterson, I presume?
我不会回到那去的
I'm not going back there.
你别无选择
You don't have much of a choice.
放松...
Easy...
我回到那去, 我就会被感染. 这是谋杀
I go back there, I get infected. That's murder.
一旦我们确定你没有受到感染
Once we ensure that you are not infected,
你会被允许返回城市
you will be allowed back into the city.
在那之前, 你对其他人来说都是一个威胁
Until then, you are a threat
to the rest of the population.
你不会朝自己人开枪的
You won't shoot a member of your own team.
Peterson, 你没被允许回到城市
Peterson, you will not be allowed
to go back to the city.
等等, 等等. 就等一会儿
Wait, wait. Just wait a second.
把我带回医学实验室
把我隔离在那儿. 我可以自己过去.
Take me back to the med lab.
just quarantine me there. I'll go voluntarily.
求你了, 不要让我回到那去
Just, please, don't make me go back there.
事实上, 我很好. 我感觉非常好.
Really, I'm fine. I feel perfectly fine.
Weir博士, 我是Sheppard.
Dr. Weir, this is Sheppard.
Peterson已经同意回到医学实验室
直到我们搞定当前的情况
Peterson has agreed to go back to the med lab
until we can get the situation resolved.
站住!
Stop!
噢, 天哪!
Oh, my god!
他中枪了
He's been shot.
发生什么了?
What's going on?
古人的控制器没有反映了
Ancient controls are unresponsive.
我接到报告Peterson已经被传送到了餐厅了
I'm getting reports that Peterson
transported into the mess hall.
处于某种原因, 我们无法跟着他
For some reason, we can't follow him.
这个城市被接管了...
The city has taken over...
把我们投入一级防范状态
put us into a lockdown.
- 超驰自动控制
- 我做不到
- Override it.
- I can't.
Atlantis一定被设计用来可以自动应对疾病的爆发
Atlantis must be designed
to respond to outbreaks automatically.
当Peterson从东边传送出来时
城市的一级防范就被启动了
The city initiated a lockdown when Peterson
transported out of the east side.
为什么是现在?
Why now?
为什么不是当Johnson和Wagner被感染的时候?
Why not when Johnson and Wagner became infected?
那些区域的传感系统可能受到了洪水的影响
The city's detection systems might have been
affected by the flooding in those areas...
不过当Peterson进入餐厅时
But once Peterson entered the mess hall,
病原体几乎立刻就被自动系统检测到了
the pathogen was almost instantly
detected by automated systems,
城市立刻就开始保护自己
and the city protected itself.
好吧, 我现在有什么选择?
All right, what are my options?
很少
Limited.
正如现在, 我们完全被隔离在主机之外了
As of now, we're completely
locked out of the mainframe.
这是真的么?
我将会死于脑动脉瘤
Is this really necessary?
I am about to die of a brain aneurysm.
装上心脏监视器有什么用?
How does being attached to a heart monitor help?
如果你想其他人那样死去,
我们将会更清楚其中的过程.
If you die like the others,
we'll have a better idea of how.
这么说, 我就不在意了
At that point, I will cease to care.
还有很多其他人住在这个城市, 伙计
There are a lot of other people
that live in the city, man.
是的, 活着的
Yes, the living.
我本以为我们被锁死了
I thought we were in a lockdown.
那个门为什么为我们打开?
Why'd that open up for us?
Weir, 我是Sheppard.
Weir, this is Sheppard.
你现在可以把传送器联机么?
Were you able to get the transporters online or not?
看起来没有希望
It doesn't look promising.
Atlantis自己好像已经探测到了威胁
然后接管了大部分控制
Atlantis itself seems to have somehow sensed
a threat and taken over most of the controls.
所以它关闭了传送器?
So it shut down the transporters?
是这样
That's right.
好吧, 我想我们应该考虑到这个
Well, I wish we would have thought of that.
我们确实考虑到了, 少校
We did think of that, Major.
为了你们, 必须给整个区域供电
以打开通往Peterson的大门
That entire section had to be powered up
for you to open the door to Peterson.
事实上, 如果你们没有跟着他
In fact, if you hadn't gone after him,
他也本可以不使用那些传送器的.
he wouldn't have been able to use the transporters.
你现在还认为这是一个好主意么?
Do you still feel it was a good idea?
传送器去了哪里?
Where'd he transport to?
餐厅
The mess hall.
感谢上帝, 其他人都很尊重隔离
Thankfully, everyone else respected the quarantine.
只有少数人在那里
There's only a handful of people there.
好了, 你已经说清楚了
All right, you've made your point.
你们赶快回到城市来
Make your way back to the city.
在Beckett的实验室等进一步指示
Wait in Beckett's lab for further instructions.
Beckett博士?
Dr. Beckett?
有什么进展么, Biro博士?
Any progress, Dr. Biro?
刚刚完成Dumais的尸体解剖
Just finished Dumais' autopsy.
如果告诉您她也死于动脉破裂, 您会感到奇怪么?
Would it surprise you to learn she died of a ruptured
视觉皮层的大脑动脉瘤, 先生?
brain aneurysm above the visual cortex, sir?
不, 我不会奇怪
谢谢你, 博士
No, it wouldn't. Thank you, Doctor.
不客气
Didn't think so.
血管破裂的位置可以解释那些幻觉
You know, the position of
the rupture could explain the visions.
在破裂之前, 那个区域的血流量猛增
Swelling in that area before the breakage
完全可以引起幻觉.
could absolutely account for the hallucinations.
我不是医学博士, 不过大脑视觉皮层的血流量猛增
Look, I'm no M.D., but wouldn't brain
swelling on the visual cortex
就一定会引起色彩的混乱和奇怪的视觉?
just mean that we experience
washes of color or weird visual anomalies?
这取决于个人
It would depend on the person.
Yeah, 这就是我要说的
Yeah, that's my point.
所有的幻觉都是如此的接近
All of our visions are so similar.
如果它们是动脉血流量猛增的结果
If they're the result of arterial swelling,
难道我们经历的视觉不会更随机一些么?
wouldn't the visions we experience be more random?
很可能是
Most likely.
Yeah, 那好, 我们看到的东西几乎全是一样的
Yeah, well, the things we're seeing
are pretty damn identical.
你想可能是有什么东西在起作用...
You think it might have
something to do with the nature...
Hays, 这不是真的. 记住, 这不是真的
Hays, it's not real. Remember, it's not real.
他们正朝我们过来! 你看不见它们么?
They're coming right at us! Can't you see them?
他的心率急剧上升, 不过那以后...
His heart rate's spiked, but aside from that...
不要说"好"! 他不好. 做点什么!
Don't say "fine!" He's not fine. Do something!
什么也做不了
There's nothing to do.
一, 二,
One, two,
三, 四,
three, four,
五...
five...
一, 二,
one, two,
- 三, 四, 五
- 停
- three, four, five.
- Stop.
不是他的心脏
It's not his heart.
...停
...stop.
你感觉怎么样?
How are you feeling?
我...
I'm...
听着, 我有一个妹妹
Listen, I have a sister.
- 我们并不亲近. 我甚至不知道你是否能找到她
- 不要说了
- We're not close. I don't even know how you'd find her.
- Don't talk like that.
她是我真正拥有的唯一家人,
所以一定要有人告诉她发生了什么...
She's the only family I really have,
so someone should tell her what happened...
并让这一切听起来很好, 好么?
And make it sound good, okay?
告诉她我是为了救人而死的... 救几个小孩
Tell her I died saving someone... kids.
我因救几个小孩而死, 一群小孩...
I died saving kids, a bunch of them...
另外, Zelenka, 我有一些理论
通过环接大门中的电源给用完的ZPM充电
And, Zelenka, I got some theories on looping
the power in the gate to charge a dummy ZPM.
这可能并不能工作, 但你应该让人看看
因为这也有可能会导致其他的结果
It probably won't work, but you should have someone
look at it, because it might lead somewhere else.
我们会一起去看的
We'll look at it together.
你真的要中断我最后的思考么
You seriously have
to stop interrupting my last thoughts.
我的意思是, 刚才说的都非常重要
I mean, this is important stuff you need to hear.
现在...如果你们在这里再多呆上一年
Now...if you're here for more than a year,
我会留下一些笔记
关于如何进行应对电力不足
I've left some notes on how to roll blackouts
来有效地维持你们的能源需求以及...
to effectively maintain your power requirements and...
告诉所有人我距离理论的统一只有咫尺之遥
Tell everyone that I was inches
away from a theory of unification,
而那些笔记, 它们也将不再继续, 当我救那些...的时候
but the notes, they were lost when I died saving the...
- 孩子
- 对
- kids.
- Yeah.
我应该现在就死了
I should be dead now.
你是同时碰到Dumais的?
You ran into Dumais at the same time?
完全是同时
Exactly the same time.
那么, 是的, 你应该死了
Then, yes, you should be dead.
噢, 天哪
Oh, god.
我仍然还活着
I'm still here.
是的, 你还活着
Yes, you are.
有意思
Interesting.
有意思?
Interesting?
不要想歪了, 不过...
Don't take this the wrong way, but...
为什么?
why?
正好
Exactly.
什么, 我不介意
Well, I don't care.
我是说, 我真的不介意
I mean, I really don't care.
Weir博士?
Dr. Weir?
是的, 少校?
Yes, Major?
我们已经到达城市了
We've reached the city.
不过我们没有破坏城市的隔离
But we haven't hit the city's quarantine.
你确信它把你锁在那里?
Are you sure it's locked you out?
非常肯定. 我甚至不能进入我的办公室.
Pretty sure. I can't even get into my office.
它到现在还没有给我们任何麻烦.
It hasn't giving us any trouble yet.
防护服. 他们已经受到保护了
Hazmat suits. They're protected.
什么?
What?
这个城市一定能够感觉到他们没有感染的危险
The city must be capable of sensing
they're in no danger of infection.
事实上, 这很有意义
It makes sense, actually.
照这么说, Atlantis允许
受到保护的人去帮助受到感染的人
This way, Atlantis allows
protected personnel to assist the infected.
如果是这种情况的话
我们应该可以去餐厅
If that is the case,
we should make our way to the mess hall.
我想那里的每个人一定会非常恐惧和迷惑
I imagine everyone there will be
very scared and confused.
同意
I agree.
快去餐厅, 然后发回报告
Get to the mess hall and report back.
你确信你想看这个么, Rodney?
Are you certain you really want to see this, Rodney?
太精确了
It's too accurate.
为什么有器官可以如此的高效?
How can something organic be that efficient?
再说一遍, 我们在另一个星系的中央
Again, we're in the middle of another galaxy.
只是因为它跟我们平常不同
Just because it's out of the ordinary for us
但这并不意味着它在这里就不平凡
doesn't mean it's not commonplace here.
不, 不, 不, 我不认为这样
No, no, no, I don't buy that.
我们迄今为止所遇到的大多数可居住的行星
Most of the habitable planets
we've encountered thus far
都跟地球的环境条件非常相似
are carbon copies of earth in terms
of environmental conditions.
除非...
Unless...
我就回来
I'll be back.
怎么了, Rodney?
What's up, Rodney?
潜伏直到完成需要刚好六个小时
Incubation to completion is exactly six hours.
所有受到感染的人看到的幻觉都完全相同
The visions are identical for all the infected,
而且每位死者的动脉瘤的位置都是完全一样
and the location of the aneurysm is
the same for every single deceased.
你想我认为它是什么?
Is that what I think it is?
这是纳米病毒, 每个都被造出来用以杀死人类
It's a nanovirus, one manufactured to kill humans.
纳米病毒?
A nanovirus?
对
That's right.
OK, 告诉我这到底是什么
Okay, let's pretend I don't know exactly what that is.
纳米科技... 这是操作在纳米级的科技
Nano technology... it's technology
that operates on a nanite scale.
大概是一米的十亿分之一
It's around a billionth of a millimeter.
基本上, 它们是一些精微的机器
专门完成适合它们身材的非常特殊的任务
Basically, they're microscopic machines that are able
to carry out very specific tasks suited for their size.
其结果是, 你可以吞下一枚药片
It's the whole idea of being able to swallow a pill
然后成百万的小机器人投入工作
治愈折磨你的疾病
and having a million little robots
go to work and cure whatever ails you.
你们都是被这种精微的机器感染了?
You're all infected with microscopic machines?
是的, 它们比一个单细胞生物还要小
Yeah, they're no bigger than a single-celled organism,
然而却有某一特定的作用, 如治疗疾病
although instead of having
a sole purpose of curing a disease
或者修补血管...
or mending a blood vessel...
这种病毒是被设计用来恐吓其受害者
The virus is programmed to terrorize its victims
通过侵入他们的视觉皮层
然后让大脑中的一条动脉破裂
by tapping into their visual cortex
and then rupturing an artery in their brain.
用同样的方法传染其他人
Infecting others along the way as they can.
它们是一种好东西
There's one good thing.
我怀疑它们可以复制...
I doubt they can multiply...
我不知道需要多少个才能杀死一个人
I don't know how many nanites
it takes to kill a human,
不过最后
我想它们太薄弱以致不能传播自己了
but eventually,
I imagine they'll spread themselves too thin.
这可能是幽灵做的么?
Could it be Wraith?
我开头也这么想
That would definitely be my first guess.
我不是很确信
I'm not so sure about that.
不过那个幻觉, 那个尖叫的声音
你告诉我当他们...
But the visions, the shrill sound
you told me they make when they...
我会告诉你它们也是同样可怕
I'll give you that they're equally terrifying,
不过幽灵为什么制造一个同样恐怖的WMD呢?
but why would the Wraith even
create the equivalent of a WMD?
它们杀死我们并不是因为他们想把我们虐待致死
They're killing us not because
they sadistically want us dead,
只是因为作为食物, 他们需要消耗我们
but because they need to consume us for food.
瞧, 这就等同于养牛的农场主制造疯牛病. 我可不会去买
Look, it would be like the equivalent of cattle
farmers creating mad cow disease. I don't buy it.
你确实是从古人的实验室中发现这个的
You did come across it in an Ancient lab.
什么, 那么, 断绝幽灵的食物供给
是最后走投无路的想法?
What, so, wiping out the Wraith's food
supply is a last-ditch consideration?
我从来不这么想
I don't believe that for a moment.
古人绝对不会造出这种东西
The ancients would never create something like this.
这也无法解释那个幻觉
That doesn't explain the visions, either.
好吧, 现在, 谁制造了这个病毒
并不是我们现在所需要关注的
Okay, for the moment, who built the virus
is really the least of our concerns.
说得好
Good point.
我们需要搞清楚人是如何传播这个病毒的
We have yet to determine how one contracts the virus.
很可能你们都没有被感染
It is very possible that
none of you have been infected.
那你为什么要穿防护服呢?
Then why are you in hazmat suits?
这只是预防措施
Just as a precaution.
Sheppard少校, 我是McKay.
Major Sheppard, this is McKay.
怎么了?
What is it?
到我的实验室来, 我需要你帮忙
I could use your help at my lab.
去吧. 我不会有事的.
Go. I will be fine.
我和Hays同时被感染
Hays and I were infected at the same time.
只有一种可能可以解释为什么我可以存活下来
There's only one thing that explains why I survived.
Rodney具有古人的基因, Hays却没有
Rodney has the ancient gene. Hays did not.
但是Rodney不是古人
But Rodney's not an Ancient.
对, 不过他曾经接种过A.T.A.基因
Aye, but he's been inoculated with the A.T.A. Gene.
你是说这种病毒是被专门设计用来杀死人类的?
You're saying the virus
is designed to only kill humans?
好吧, 我是人类
Well, I'm human.
是的, 是的
Yes, yes.
我们有个想法, Rodney.
We're making a point, Rodney.
因此我们要给每个人进行基因治疗?
So we give everyone the gene therapy?
不, 不准备这样做
No, that's not going to do it.
我在几周以前就已经被给与了这种基因
I've already been given the gene weeks ago.
但我没有带有
It didn't take.
我知道. 我已经带有了
I know. I'm already on it.
基因治疗只会在48%的接受者中起作用
The gene therapy is
only effective in 48% of recipients.
如果我现在被注射基因
If I was given the gene shot right now,
需要多久才可以奏效?
how long would it take to kick in?
至少四个小时
A minimum of four hours.
噢, 我没有四小时!
Well, I don't have four hours!
我在McKay和Hays碰到Dumais之后90分钟就遇到了他们
I met up with McKay and Hays
90 minutes after they met up with Dumais.
我还有... 不到一个小时
我的大脑就会爆炸
I have... a little under an hour
before my brain explodes.
Hayden, 听我说
Hayden, listen to me.
你现在距离出事已经有20小时了
You've been up for almost 20 hours now.
不是你想的那回事
试图冷静一些
You're not thinking straight. Just try to stay calm.
冷静?
Calm?
你告诉我我身体中有一百万个小机器人
You told me I have  a million tiny robots
沿着我的血管在跑
它们唯一的目的就是恐吓我然后杀了我
running through my veins whose
only purpose is to terrorize and kill me.
你能冷静么?
You stay calm.
你就要开始有幻觉了
We are about to have hallucinations.
我们被感染了, Carson.
We are infected, Carson.
我想我们都发作么?
How do you expect us to act?
看来必须另寻出路
There's got to be another way.
我已经告诉你了, 我正在努力
I've already told you, I am working on it.
好吧, McKay. 我在这里
All right, McKay. I'm here.
你看见它没有?
Do you see it?
是房间中央的那个大东西么?
Is it the big thing in the middle of the room?
是的, 就是那个
Yeah, that's the one.
我要注意这些警告么?
Should I pay attention to all these warnings?
不, 不需要
Not today, no.
你要做什么?
What are you going to do?
好吧, 只要它们还在这里
这些纳米机器人就会被计算机控制而运作
Well, as small as they are, the nanovirus is still
effectively just a machine run by a computer.
而最好的停掉计算机的方法就是制造一个电磁脉冲
The best way to knock out a computer
is with an electromagnetic pulse.
值得欣慰的是, 这个我们能够做到
Thankfully, that's something we can do.
我们要关掉所有我们从地球上带来的电子设备
We're about through shutting down
all the electronic gear we brought from earth.
我们仍然被锁在古人的控制器之外
We're still locked out of the Ancient controls, though.
没有办法把它们都关掉
There's no way to power them down.
好吧, 那没有必要
Well, it's not going to be necessary.
古人的技术跟我们的工作原理不同
The Ancient technology works differently than ours.
一个E.M. 脉冲不会对它造成长期影响
An E.M. Pulse shouldn't have
any long-lasting effect on it.
我们准备好了
We're ready.
我们全都就绪了, Rodney.
We're all set, Rodney.
好的... 来吧
Okay... here we go.
等等
Wait.
我们怎么知道这可以奏效?
How will we know if it works?
Sheppard将会拨出发电机所能够制造的最强大的脉冲
Well, Sheppard's dialing up the most
powerful pulse the generator can manage.
这可能不会影响全部
It probably won't make it all the way down here,
不过确实可以影响到大多数中央控制塔
but it should affect most of the central tower.
我想一旦病毒被消除掉了
I imagine once it wipes out the virus,
城市将会解除锁定, 把控制权交还给你们
the city should return control
of it to you and end the lockdown.
在这没有用吧?
It won't make it here?
如果脉冲奏效的话, 你将会到我的实验室中
If the pulse works, it'll simply be a matter
of walking you down to my lab,
坐在EMP前面, 重复以上的过程
sitting you down in front of the EMP,
and repeating the process.
少校?
Major?
开始工作了. 我应该什么时候按下放电按钮?
It's working. When I should hit the discharge button?
嗯, 应该有一个红色的过载指示灯
Okay, there should be a red overload light.
好的, 我看见了
Yeah, I see it.
等到它亮起, 数十下, 然后放电
Wait till it comes on,
give it a good 10-count, and then discharge.
数十下?
A 10-count?
别担心
Don't worry.
我可能比其他任何人在EMP前待的时间都长
I've probably been around more EMPs than anyone.
这会...
This is going to be...
会没事的, 对么?
going to be fine, right?
是的, 没事的
Yes, that's a yes.
你会没事的
You'll be fine.
有效果么?
Anything?
这是不是要等一段时间?
Is it possible it might take some time?
可能吧
Doubtful.
你仍然无法进入古人的主机?
Are you still locked out of the Ancient mainframe?
还有其他办法么?
Got any other ideas?
29分钟
29 minutes.
这没有用, 这没有用
It didn't work. It didn't work.
仍然没有清除干净
It is still unclear.
什么没有干净?
What's unclear?
要么它有效, 要么就没有
Either it worked or it didn't.
他们正在试图找出...
They are trying to determine...
他们到处都是!
They're everywhere!
你正在经历一场幻觉.
You are experiencing a hallucination.
噢, 我的天哪
Oh, my god.
我已经试过了. 这没有用
I've already tried that. It's blown.
那是在我们重置子开关之前
That is before we reset the sub-switch.
好吧, 也许我们不应该过载那么多
Well, maybe we shouldn't have overloaded it so much.
这是固定的, 这是固定的
Look, it's fixable. It's fixable.
我们只是需要使用一点点尝试和错误
We just need to use a little trial and error.
即使我们让这东西工作起来
Look, even if we get this thing working,
谁能够说脉冲可以获得更大呢?
who's to say the pulse is going to get any bigger?
好吧, Ford和Zelenka只剩下20分钟了
All right, Ford and Zelenka have 20 minutes
before their arteries rupture.
你确信EMP会杀死这东西?
Are you sure an EMP will kill this thing?
是的
Yes.
好吧, 我有一个主意
All right, I have an idea.
你这是什么意思, "不"?
What do you mean, "no"?
这太危险了
It's too dangerous.
你想我们当中三分之一的人死去么?
You'd rather lose a third of our population?
我们还没到那个地步, 少校
We're not there yet, Major.
我们已经到了!
We are there!
Ford和Zelenka就是下一波了
Ford and Zelenka are next.
餐厅中的人只有三个小时多一点时间了
The people in the mess hall have
a little over three hours.
这是一次完全的爆发
This is a full-blown outbreak.
如果我们不这样做, 就会不断有人死去
People are going to keep dying unless we do this.
即使我们把EMP发电机重新联机
Even if we were able to get
the EMP generator back online,
我们让它足够强大的机会也是微乎其微
the chances are slim that we would
ever be able to get it powerful enough.
我们不能把受感染的人带到发电机那里去么?
Can we bring the infected to the generator?
不能
We can't.
城市不会让受到感染的人通过任何一道门
The city won't let infected personnel
through any of the doors.
少校是对的
The major is right.
唯一可以制造足以消灭这些家伙的EMP的办法就是...
The only way to create an EMP
strong enough to wipe these little guys out is...
在大气中引爆一次核爆炸
to detonate a nuclear explosion in the atmosphere, yes.
我还是第一次听说
I heard the first time.
我知道这听起来很严重
I know it sounds severe,
不过如果少校可以在离城市20英里远的地方引爆
but if the major was able to overload
a naquadah generator 20 miles above the city,
从发射学的立场看, 我们是非常安全的
we'd be perfectly safe from a radiological standpoint,
并且可以保证爆炸能够制作一个
具有强大破坏力的电磁冲击波
and the ensuing blast would be capable of creating
a devastating electromagnetic shock wave.
足够消除这些病毒
Definitely enough to knock this virus out.
希望不要摧毁我们自己的计算机设备
Hopefully without destroying
all our own computer equipment.
这值得冒一下险
It's worth the risk.
好吧, 你可以出发了
Okay, you have a go.
我已经就位了
I'm almost in position.
明白
Understood.
E.M.脉冲对飞船会有什么影响么?
Will the E.M. Pulse have any
effect on the puddle jumper?
希望没有
I'm hoping not.
无论如何, 我还是担心冲击波
Either way, I'm more worried about the shock wave.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你也是
You too.
在你放出它之后, 你只有30秒钟逃命
You're only going to have 30 seconds
once you release it before it explodes.
你需要尽可能飞远一些
You need to get as far away as you can.
离核爆炸越远越好
Get as far away from
the nuclear explosion as possible.
这是个好建议, Rodney. 多谢
That's good advice, Rodney. Thanks.
不客气
You're welcome.
我准备释放发生器了...
I'm releasing the generator...
现在
now.
25秒后引爆
Detonation in 25 seconds.
20 秒...
20 seconds...
15 秒...
15 seconds...
10 秒后引爆...
detonation in 10...
9, 8, 7...
nine, eight, seven...
6...
six...
5...
five...
4, 3, 2...
four, three, two...
one.
Sheppard少校, 请回答
Major Sheppard, come in.
我是Weir. 请回答
This is Weir. Please respond.
通讯可能会受到爆炸的干扰
Communications may have been disrupted by the blast.
少校, 能听到么?
Major, do you read me?
我是Sheppard.
This is Sheppard.
我已经从爆炸中出来了
I've cleared the blast.
我正在回家的途中
I'm returning home.
很高兴听到你的声音, 少校
Glad to hear it, Major.
奏效了么?
Did it work?
我们正在检查
We're about to find out.
我们应该马上就可以知道
We should know almost right away.
脉冲只持续了两微秒...
The pulse only lasts a couple of microseconds...
城市已经回到我们手中了, Rodney.
The city is already ahead of us, Rodney.
你可以放心回来了
You have a green light to return.
你还好吧?
You all right?
还好吧?
You okay?
是的, 只是一个小核弹. 没有什么, 真的.
Yeah, just a little nuke. Nothin', really.
这个计划真是聪明
The naquadah generator plan was very clever.
- 干得好
- 谢谢你
- Good work.
- Thank you.
现在我要去睡觉了
Now I'm going to bed.
我们需要讨论一下早先发生的事情
We need to discuss what happened earlier.
现在?
Now?
以后再也不能发生了类似的事情了
That can never happen again.
我很抱歉...
Look, I'm sorry about...
我了解你在处理军事事务中的经验
I understand your expertise in military matters,
并且我也同意我应该在
类似的情况中推迟这些经验的实施...
and I agree that I should defer
to those expertise in such situations...
谢谢
Thank you.
不过你还不是那个判断到底是不是军事状况的那个人
But you are not the one who decides what is
and what is not a military situation.
O'Neill将军和Sumner上校
Now, both general O'Neill and colonel Sumner
都曾经警告过我你并不是非常尊重上级的命令
warned me that you don't respect
the proper chain of command.
有些时候, 我所看到的情况跟你稍微一点不同
Sometimes, I see a situation
a little different than you.
不, 听我说, John
No, listen to me, John.
如今, 你把你自己和很多其他人的生命推入险境
Now, you endangered yourself
and the lives of many others.
因为我认为到了采取行动的最佳时机了
Because I thought it was
the best course of action to take,
而且, 顺便说一句, 我救了你的命
and, by the way, I saved your ass.
我知道你所做的...
I know you did...
不过你必须相信我
but you have to trust me.
我相信
I do.
是么?
Do you?
你们有时间么?
You guys have a minute?
我们可以花些时间来研究那些纳米病毒样品了
We've been able to spend some
quality time with the nanovirus samples.
据我们所知, 它们全部已经失去能力了
From what we can tell,
they've all been incapacitated.
好啊, 这是个好消息
Well, that's good news.
是的, 另外, 根据进一步的研究
Yes, also, upon further investigation,
我想我们可以排除它们是由幽灵制造的可能性了
I think we can rule out that
they were created by the Wraith.
他们跟我们以前碰到的任何幽灵的科技都不相同
They're different than any Wraith technology
we've come across thus far.
如果不是幽灵...
If not the Wraith...
那么是谁制造了他们?
then who made them?
老实说我也不知道
I honestly don't know.
不管它们是谁, 只希望他们不要在周围
Whoever they were, let's just hope
that they're not still around.
但愿吧
Let's hope.